Guide to the Arlin Turner Papers, 1927-1980 RL.01312
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1930-1980
  - Publications Subseries, 1934-1979
    - Hawthorne: A Biography (Box 4)
    - Literary Classics - Library of America (Box 4)
    - Louisiana State University Press (Box 4)
    - Modern Fiction Studies (Box 4)
    - Nathaniel Hawthorne Journal (Box 4)
    - New England Quarterly (Box 4)
    - Nineteenth-Century Fiction (Box 4)
    - Penn State University Press (Box 4)
    - Princeton University Press (Box 4)
    - Resources for American Literary Study (Box 4)
    - (William Gilmore) Simms Edition (Box 4)
    - Stark Young by Pilkington (Box 4)
    - University of Massachusetts Press (Box 4)
    - University of North Carolina Press (Box 4)
    - University of Tennessee Press (Box 4)
    - University Press of Kansas (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous publications correspondence (Box 4)
  - Conferences, Speeches, Lectures Subseries, 1961-1978 (bulk 1961-1964)
    Correspondence regarding Turner's speaking engagements and attendance at professional gatherings is collected in the Conferences, Speeches, and Lectures Subseries. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - box 5 (Box 5)
    - 1961: University of Michigan - Civil War Lecture Series (Box 5)
    - 1961: Kent State University - Lecture (Box 5)
    - 1962: Duke University - N.C. Junior Science Symposium (Box 5)
    - 1962: Duke University - Seminar, The Two Cultures (Box 5)
    - 1963: Atlanta University - Forum Series (Box 5)
    - 1963: University of Michigan - Seminar on English in Contemporary Education (Box 5)
    - 1963-1964: Conference on the Integrated Bibliography (Box 5)
    - 1964: Bowdoin College Institute - Hawthorne and the American Novel (Box 5)
    - 1964: Duke University - Seminar, Humanities and the Arts (Box 5)
    - 1964: Project on [High School] Literature Conference (Box 5)
    - 1972: Conference on Southern Literary Study (Box 5)
    - 1975: Duke Alumni Summer Institute - Lecture (Box 5)
    - 1978: West Virginia University - Symposium on Regional Research in the Humanities (Box 5)
  - Other Correspondence Subseries, 1948-1979 and undated
    Miscellaneous files that contain primarily correspondence can be found in the Other Correspondence Subseries. Many of these files relate either to Duke University or to universities at which Turner served as a visiting professor. These are organized by the subject or addressee of the correspondence and arranged alphabetically, with correspondence from international scholars in American literature filed at the end.
    - Cable, (George Washington) Research, undated, 2 folders (Box 5 (cont))
    - Duke University. Gross-Edens Affair, 1960 (Box 5 (cont))
    - Duke University Library, Misc., 1950, 1975, 1978 (Box 5 (cont))
    - Duke University Library - Harold Jantz Collection, 1975 (Box 5 (cont))
    - Duke University Research Council Grants, 1954-1977 (Box 5 (cont))
    - Duke Summer Grants-in-aid, Visiting Scholars, 1965, 1969-1970 (Box 5 (cont))
    - Fulbright Applications and Correspondence, 1955-1965 (Box 6)
    - Fulbright Award - University of Hull, Hull, England, 1965-1966 (Box 6)
    - Huntington Fellowship, 1973-1978 (Box 6)
    - Huntington Library, 1968-1977 (Box 6)
    - Huntington Research, undated (Box 6)
    - Louisiana State University Library, 1950-1952 (Box 6)
    - National Book Awards, 1969 (Box 6)
    - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) Institutes, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
    - National Humanities Center, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - New York University, 1964 (Box 6)
    - New York Library, 1948-1956, 1964-1976 (Box 6)
    - N.C. State University, Dept. of English, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Quality Education Bill (HR11888), 1962 (Box 6)
    - Southern American Writers Cassette Curriculum, 1975 (Box 6)
    - University Centers for Rational Alternatives (UCRA), 1969-1978 (Box 6)
    - University of Hull, Hull, England, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
    - University of Illinois, 1961 (Box 6)
    - University of Iowa, 1963 (Box 6)
    - University of Montreal, 1951, [contains photographs of Turner, Thomas Greenwood] (Box 6)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Indian Specialists in American Literature, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
    - Asian Specialists in American Literature, 1962-1963 (Box 6)
    - South African Specialists in American Literature, 1958-1963 (Box 6)
- Course Materials Series, undated
  The Course Materials Series is divided into three subseries. The first two subseries are comprised of Lecture Notes, arranged by Author and Subject. The last contains Class Files. Only the first of these subseries preserves Turner's original arrangement.
  - Lecture Notes, By Author Subseries, undated
    Each folder in the Lecture Notes, By Author Subseries contains the materials on various literary figures that Turner appears to have collected for classroom use. Almost all of these include a brief typed page containing the author's birth and death dates and significant writings. Most are also accompanied by a brief typed biography and summary of the author's contribution to literature. Some folders may also contain copies of an author's works, especially poetry, or newspaper clippings about them, in addition to Turner's personal research. These are arranged alphabetically in the same order that Turner filed them.
    - box 7 (Box 7)
    - Adams, Henry (Box 7)
    - Albee, Edward (Box 7)
    - Allen, James Lane (Box 7)
    - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 7)
    - Applewhite, James (Box 7)
    - Audubon, John James (Box 7)
    - Bagby, George William (Box 7)
    - Baldwin, James (Box 7)
    - Baldwin, Joseph G. (Box 7)
    - Barlow, Joel (Box 7)
    - Bellamy, Edward (Box 7)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent (Box 7)
    - Beverley, Robert (Box 7)
    - Bevington, Helen (Box 7)
    - Bonner, Sherwood (Box 7)
    - Brackenridge, Hugh Henry (Box 7)
    - Bradford, Roark (Box 7)
    - Bradford, William (Box 7)
    - Bradstreet, Anne (Box 7)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 7)
    - Brown, Charles Brockden (Box 7)
    - Brown, Charles Farrar (a.k.a. Artemus Ward) (Box 7)
    - Bryant, William Cullen (Box 7)
    - Byrd, William (Box 7)
    - Cabell, James Branch (Box 7)
    - Cable, George Washington (Box 7)
    - Capote, Truman (Box 7)
    - Caldwell, Erskine (Box 7)
    - Cather, Willa (Box 7)
    - Cawein, Madison (Box 7)
    - Chappell, Fred (Box 7)
    - Chivers, Thomas Holley (Box 7)
    - Chopin, Kate (Box 7)
    - Clemens, Samuel L. (a.k.a. Mark Twain) (Box 7)
    - Cooke, John Esten (Box 7)
    - Cooper, James Fenimore (Box 7)
    - Crane, Hart (Box 7)
    - Crane, Stephen (Box 7)
    - Crevecoeur, Michel-Guillarme Jean de (Box 7)
    - Crockett, Davy (Box 7)
    - Cummings, E.E. (Box 7)
    - Davidson, Donald (Box 7)
    - Dickey, James (Box 7)
    - Dickenson, Emily (Box 7)
    - Dixon, Thomas (Box 7)
    - Dobie, J. Frank (Box 7)
    - Dos Passos, John R. (Box 7)
    - Dreiser, Theodore (Box 7)
    - Dunne, Finley Peter (Box 7)
    - Dykeman (Stokley), Wilma (Box 7)
    - Eberhart, Richard (Box 7)
    - Edwards, Harry Stillwell (Box 7)
    - box 8 (Box 8)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 8)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Box 8)
    - Flint, Timothy (Box 8)
    - Franklin, Benjamin (Box 8)
    - Frederic, Harold (Box 8)
    - Freeman, Mary E. Wilkins (Box 8)
    - Freneau, Philip (Box 8)
    - Farrell, James T. (Box 8)
    - Frost, Robert (Box 8)
    - Garland, Hamlin (Box 8)
    - George, Henry (Box 8)
    - Grady, Henry W. (Box 8)
    - Grayson, William John (Box 8)
    - Green, Paul (Box 8)
    - Harris, George Washington (Box 8)
    - Harris, Joel Chandler (Box 8)
    - Harte, F. Bret (Box 8)
    - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 13 folders (Box 8)
    - Hayne, P. H. (Box 8)
    - Hearn, Lafcadio (Box 8)
    - Hemingway, Ernest (Box 8)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Box 8)
    - Hooper, Johnson Jones (Box 8)
    - Hope, James Barron (Box 8)
    - Howells, William Dean (Box 8)
    - Hughes, Langston (Box 8)
    - Irving, Washington (Box 8)
    - box 9 (Box 9)
    - Jacobsen, Josephine (Box 9)
    - James, Henry (Box 9)
    - Jarrell, Randall (Box 9)
    - Jeffers, Robinson (Box 9)
    - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 9)
    - Jewett, Sarah Orne (Box 9)
    - Johnston, Richard Malcolm (Box 9)
    - Kennedy, John Pendleton (Box 9)
    - King, Grace E. (Box 9)
    - Kizer, Carolyn (Box 9)
    - Lanier, Sidney (Box 9)
    - Legare, James M. (Box 9)
    - Levertov, Denise (Box 9)
    - Lewis, Sinclair (Box 9)
    - Lewis, Henry Clay (a.k.a. Madison Tensas) (Box 9)
    - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 9)
    - Lindsay, Vachel (Box 9)
    - London, Jack (Box 9)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth (Box 9)
    - Longstreet, Augustus Baldwin (Box 9)
    - Lowell, Amy (Box 9)
    - Lowell, James Russell (Box 9)
    - Lowell, Robert (Box 9)
    - McCullers, Carson (Box 9)
    - McKenna, Richard (Box 9)
    - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 9)
    - Melville, Herman, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Mencken, H.L. (Box 9)
    - Merton, Thomas (Box 9)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent (Box 9)
    - Miller, Arthur (Box 9)
    - Miller, Joaquin (Box 9)
    - Momaday, N. Scott (Box 9)
    - Moody, William Vaughn (Box 9)
    - Murfree, Mary Noailles (a.k.a. Charles Egbert Craddock) (Box 9)
    - Norris, Frank (Box 9)
    - O'Connor, Flannery (Box 9)
    - O'Hara, Theodore (Box 9)
    - O'Neill, Eugene G. (Box 9)
    - Owen, Guy (Box 9)
    - box 10 (Box 10)
    - Page, T.N. (Box 10)
    - Paine, Thomas (Box 10)
    - Parkman, Francis (Box 10)
    - Patton, Francis Gray (Box 10)
    - Paulding, J.K. (Box 10)
    - Payne, John Howard (Box 10)
    - Peck, Samuel M. (Box 10)
    - Peterkin, Julia (Box 10)
    - Pike, Albert (Box 10)
    - Pinkney, Edward Coote (Box 10)
    - Poe, Edgar Allan, 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne (Box 10)
    - Porter, William Sydney (a.k.a. O. Henry) (Box 10)
    - Pound, Ezra (Box 10)
    - Preston, Margaret Junkin (Box 10)
    - Price, Reynolds (Box 10)
    - Randall, James Ryder (Box 10)
    - Randolph, Innes (Box 10)
    - Ransom, John Crowe (Box 10)
    - Rawlings, Marjorie Kinnan (Box 10)
    - Roberts, Elizabeth Madox (Box 10)
    - Robinson, Edwin Arlington (Box 10)
    - Roethke, Theodore (Box 10)
    - Rogers, Will (Box 10)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 10)
    - Russell, Irwin (Box 10)
    - Ryan, Father Abram (Box 10)
    - Salinger, J. D. (Box 10)
    - Sandburg, Carl (Box 10)
    - Sewall, Samuel (Box 10)
    - Shapiro, Karl (Box 10)
    - Simms, William Gilmore (Box 10)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Box 10)
    - box 11 (Box 11)
    - Smith, Betty (Box 11)
    - Smith, Charles Henry (a.k.a. Bill Arp) (Box 11)
    - Smith, F. Hopkinson (Box 11)
    - Smith, John (Box 11)
    - Smith, Lillian (Box 11)
    - Smith, Seba (Box 11)
    - Spencer, Elizabeth (Box 11)
    - Steinbeck, John (Box 11)
    - Stem, Thad (Box 11)
    - Stevens, Wallace (Box 11)
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher (Box 11)
    - Stuart, Jesse (Box 11)
    - Stuart, Ruth McHenry (Box 11)
    - Styron, William (Box 11)
    - Tabb, John Barrister (Box 11)
    - Tate, J.O. Allen (Box 11)
    - Taylor, Edward (Box 11)
    - Taylor, John (Box 11)
    - Taylor, Peter H. (Box 11)
    - Thompson, John Reuben (Box 11)
    - Thompson, William T. (Box 11)
    - Thompson, Maurice (Box 11)
    - Thoreau, Henry David (Box 11)
    - Thorpe, Thomas Bangs (Box 11)
    - Thurber, James (Box 11)
    - Ticknor, Francis Orray (Box 11)
    - Timrod, Henry (Box 11)
    - Toklas, Alice (Box 11)
    - Tourgée, Albion (Box 11)
    - Tuckerman, Frederick Goddard (Box 11)
    - Tyler, Anne (Box 11)
    - Tyler, Royall (Box 11)
    - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 11)
    - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 11)
    - Washington, Booker T. (Box 11)
    - Welty, Eudora (Box 11)
    - Wharton, Edith (Box 11)
    - White, E.B. (Box 11)
    - Whitman, Walt, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf (Box 11)
    - Wilber, Richard (Box 11)
    - Wilde, Richard Henry (Box 11)
    - Wilder, Thornton (Box 11)
    - Williams, Tennessee (Box 11)
    - Williams, William Carlos (Box 11)
    - Wilson, Augusta Evans (Box 11)
    - Wilson, Edmund (Box 11)
    - Wilson, Robert Burns (Box 11)
    - Winters, Yvor (Box 11)
    - Wolfe, Thomas (Box 11)
    - Woolman, John (Box 11)
    - Wright, James (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Authors (Box 11)
  - Lecture Notes, By Subject Subseries, undated
    The Lecture Notes, By Subject Subseries contain Turner's collected notes or clippings on general subjects in literature, delineated either by geographic region or genre. This subseries also includes files on a few non-American writers (specifically William Shakespeare, John Milton, and Edmund Spenser). The Minor Southern Authors folder, although it contains unfinished notes pages for individual authors, was not originally filed in the Lecture Notes By Author subseries and therefore is filed by subject in this subseries. The miscellaneous materials in Box 13 pertain to the English curriculum at Duke and LSU, especially degree requirements, preliminary exam questions, and stylesheets for term papers and theses at the two universities.
    - American Literature, 12 folders (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 11 folders; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Class Files Subseries, undated
    The Class Files Subseries contains Turner's teaching materials for specific classes that he taught, both at Duke and as a visiting professor elsewhere. Also included in this subseries is at least one syllabus on West Texas State letterhead that appears to be from a class in which Turner was enrolled as an undergraduate in 1927. When possible, the course numbers for these classes have been identified; it should be noted that Turner often taught the same course subject under a different number at a different institution. These files primarily contain syllabi, exams, quizes, reading lists, and lecture materials developed for a specific course.
    - Class Files, 17 folders (Box 14)
- Organizations Series, 1929-1979 (bulk 1936-1979)
  The Organizations Series contains Turner's files on professional and scholarly associations, committees, councils and societies to which he belonged, and, in many cases, led in some capacity. (For a list of Turner's most significant posts, please see the Organizational Service Biography in the Biographical Note above.) Folders in this series primarily contain correspondence, minutes, memoranda, reports, and printed matter such as newsletters, brochures, and clippings. These are arranged alphabetically.
  - box 15 (Box 15)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1957-1958 and undated (Box 15)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) - Misc., 1960-1968 and undated
    - Fellowship Selection Committee, 1962-1968 (Box 15)
    - Meeting on Scholarly Communication, 1973-1975 (Box 15)
    - Regional Associate reports, 1957-1966 (Box 15)
    - International Fellows, at Duke, 1962-1965, 1977 (Box 15)
  - American Humor Studies Association (AHSA), 1975-1977, undated (Box 15)
  - American Literature Board of Editors, 1949-1956, 1962, 1967-1970, 1975-1978, 3 folders
    - American Literature Promotional Materials, 1929 (Box 15)
  - American Studies Research Centre (ASRC), Hyderabad, India, 1965-1969 (Box 15)
  - American Studies Association (ASA) - General, 1951-1979, 4 folders
    - Bibliography Committee, 1954-1959 (Box 15)
    - Convention, Oct., 1971 (Box 15)
    - Executive Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 15)
    - Executive Committee, 1958-1961 (Box 16)
    - Executive Council, 1955-1962, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Nominating Committee, 1955, 1961 (Box 16)
    - Lower Mississippi Conference, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Radical Caucus, 1969-1971 (Box 16)
    - Development of American Studies at Duke, 1960, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Association for Canadian Studies in the U.S. (ACSUS), 1971 (Box 16)
  - Association of Chairmen of Departments of English in Colleges and Universities (CDE)/ Association of Departments of English (ADE), 1962-1965
    - CDE/MLA/NCTE Allerton Park Conference, 1962 (Box 16)
  - Center for Southern Studies, 1964-1970, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - College English Association (CEA), 1963-1971, 1974, 1979, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - College Language Association (CLA), 1965 (Box 16)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils (CBC). Committee on International Exchange of Persons (CIEP) - Misc., 1976-1977 (Box 17)
    [changed to Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) in 1975.]
    - Committee on American Studies, 1956-1963, 1968-1969, 8 folders (Box 17)
    - Conference on Federal Funding of Programs in International Education, 1968 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence - Russell, Trusten W., 1968-1969 (Box 17)
    - American Studies: An International Newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - Faculty Fulbright Advisors/Alumni Workshop, 1975 (Box 17)
  - Council of Graduate Schools (CGS) - Consulting, 1969-1975 (Box 18)
  - Duke University, Dept. of English, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Duke University Library, G.W. Flowers Memorial Collection Committee, 1955-1977, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Duke University Library, Jay B. Hubbell Center Organizing and Directing Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 18)
  - Educational Testing Service (ETS)
    - GRE Advanced Literature Test Committee, 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Scarlet Letter Test, 1964 (Box 18)
  - Ellen Glasgow Society, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Essex Institute, 1972-1978 (Box 18)
  - Fédération Internationale des Langues et Littératures Modernes (FILLM), 1963-1969 (Box 18)
  - International Association of University Professors of English (IAUPE), 1961-1977 (Box 18)
  - Institute of American Studies (West Virginia Wesleyan College), 1959 (Box 18)
  - Louisiana State University, Dept. of English, 1937-1952, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Marquis Library Society, 1969-1974 (Box 18)
  - Melville Society of America, 1973, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Modern Humanities Research Association (MHRA), 1966-1969, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Modern Language Association (MLA) - Misc., 1965-1971, undated, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - American Literature Group (ALG) - General, 1936-1954, 1961-1963, 9 folders
      - Committee on Curricula, 1950-1951 (Box 19)
      - Committee on Definitive Editions, 1950-1951 (Box 19)
      - Committee on Library Manuscript Holdings, 1950-1951 (Box 19)
      - Committee on a Monographic Series, 1950-1951 (Box 19)
      - Committee on Resources for Research, 1950-1951 (Box 19)
      - Committee on Trends in Research, 1949-1952 (Box 19)
    - American Literature Section (ALS) - General, 1967-1979, 3 folders
      - Program Planning, 1966-1967 (Box 20)
    - British Commonwealth Literature Conference, 1958 (Box 20)
    - Center for Editions of American Authors (CEAA), 1968-1973, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Conference on Scholarly Editions of American Authors, 1962 (Box 20)
    - Conference on Southern Literature, 1958-1959 (Box 20)
    - New University Conference, 1968-1969 (Box 20)
    - PMLA (Box 20)
    - Scholar's Library Selection Committee, 1968-1971 (Box 20)
  - Nathaniel Hawthorne Society, 1980, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) - Misc., 1969-1976
    - Establishment, 1965 (National Foundation for the Arts and Sciences Act) (Box 20)
    - Senior Fellowship Award, 1972-1974 (Box 20)
    - Division of Fellowships, 1967-1979
      - Summer Seminars for College Teachers, 1976-1977 (Box 20)
    - Division of Public Programs, 1971-1977
      - Media Program Panel, 1976 (Box 20)
    - Division of Research Grants, 1975-1978 (Box 21)
  - National Council of Teachers of English (NCTE), 1947, 1958, 1960-1970, 10 folders
    - Advisory Council, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Commission on Literature, 1964-1968, 5 folders (Box 22)
    - Committee on the Education of College Teachers of English, 1963-1964 (Box 22)
    - Conference on English Education, 1964, 1966 (Box 22)
    - Copyright Law (HR4347), 1965 (Box 22)
    - English Teacher Preparation Study, 1965 (Box 22)
  - North Carolina Literary and Historical Association (NCLHA), 1959-1960, 1963, 1971-1978, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - North Carolina English Teachers Association (NCETA), 1954-1957, 1964-1970, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Poe Studies Association (PSA), 1977-1978 (Box 23)
  - Popular Culture Association (PCA), 1971 (Box 23)
  - Society of American Historians, 1950-1958, 1960-1967, 1970-1978, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Society for the Study of Southern Literature (SSSL), 1974-1975, 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - South Atlantic Modern Language Association (SAMLA)
    - American Literature Section, 1954-1957, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Panel on Publishing, 1973-1975 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960, 1977 (Box 23)
  - South Atlantic Quarterly Board of Editors, 1955-1972, 6 folders (Box 23)
  - South-Central Modern Language Association (SCMLA), 1953-1971, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Southeastern American Studies Association (SEASA), 1955-1966, 1972-1978, 8 folders (Box 24)
  - Southern Historical Association (Journal of Southern History), 1948-1955, 1975 (Box 24)
  - Southern Humanities Conference, 1955-1957, 1965 (Box 24)
  - Sut Society, 1962, 1965 (Box 24)
- Printed Material Series, undated
  The Printed Material Series is comprised of clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, reprints, and publications related to American Literature. This series includes materials from the Educational Testing Service (ETS), memorabilia from Turner's time at the University of Hull in England, literary magazines, and miscellaneous clippings primarily regarding Southern writers (specifically North Carolina authors), William Faulkner, and the New Critics (aka The Fugitives).
  - Printed Materials, 15 folders (Box 25)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1938-1980 and undated (bulk 1964-1977)
  The Writings and Speeches Series is comprised primarily of copies of Turner's speeches, articles, and abstracts, as well as correspondence and contractual information regarding them. This series also includes a complete typed manuscript of Turner's Hawthorne biography with handwritten edits. The Writings and Speeches Series also contains two folders of writings about Turner: one folder of materials which Turner himself authored or compiled, including several versions of his curriculum vita and a brief autobiography with transcripts attached, and one folder of materials written by others, including tributes and obituaries. Turner's writings are arranged chronologically at the front of the box, followed by writings by others.
  - Turner's Writings
    - 1938, Fiction of the Bayou Country, The Saturday Review (Box 26)
    - 1952-1954, 1969 and undated, Speech Notes - Misc. (Box 26)
    - 1964, Problems of Literary Authorship in the South Since the Civil War, Simpson College Lecture (Box 26)
    - 1965, William Faulkner and the Revolution in Southern Literature, Mars Hill College Symposium (Box 26)
    - 1965-1973, American Bibliographic Center Abstracts (Box 26)
    - 1970, Local Color Writing in the South, 1865-1900, Indiana University Lecture (Box 26)
    - 1973, Comedy and Reality in Local Color Fiction, 1865-1900, Voice of America Forum Series (Comic Imagination in American Literature) (Box 26)
    - 1980, Nathaniel Hawthorne: A biography (typescript) (Box 26)
    - undated, Writings - Misc. (Box 26)
    - 1980 and undated, Arlin Turner, Writings about, by Turner (Box 26)
  - Writings By Others
    - 1977, 1980, Arlin Turner, Writings about, by others, [contains transparency of Turner, 1977] (Box 26)
    - 1975, Hampden-Sydney Literary Symposium Manuscript (Box 26)
    - 1976, Doonesbury,The Art of Garry Trudeau (Student Paper) (Box 26)
    - undated, Misc. (Box 26)